Alright, welcome back everyone.  Sound okay?  Alright.
好的，欢迎大家回来。听起来还好吗？好的。
So today we will-  We talked a little bit about neural networks, started to talk about neural networks yesterday.
所以今天我们将 - 我们谈了一些神经网络，昨天开始讨论神经网络。
Today we'll continue to talk about neural networks that work with images, convolutional neural networks,
今天我们将继续谈论与图像一起工作的神经网络，卷积神经网络，
and see how those types of networks can help us drive a car.  If we have time we'll cover a simple illustrative case study
并了解这些类型的网络如何帮助我们驾驶汽车。如果我们有时间，我们将涵盖一个简单的说明性案例研究
of detecting traffic lights.
检测交通灯。
The problem of detecting green, yellow, red.  If we can't teach our neural networks to do that, we're in trouble,
检测绿色，黄色，红色的问题。如果我们不能教我们的神经网络这样做，我们就麻烦了，
but it's a good, clear, illustrative case study of a three-class classification problem. Okay, next there's
但这是一个关于三类分类问题的一个好的，清晰的，说明性的案例研究。好的，接下来就是
DeepTesla here looped over and over in a very short GIF.  This is actually running live in a website right now.
DeepTesla在很短的GIF中一遍又一遍地循环。这实际上是在网站上直播。
We'll show it towards the end of the lecture, this once again just like DeepTraffic is a neural network that learns to
我们将在演讲结束时展示它，这再一次就像DeepTraffic是一个学习的神经网络
steer a vehicle based on the video of the forward road way.
根据前方道路的视频驾驶车辆。
And once again, doing all of that in the browser using javascript.
再一次，使用javascript在浏览器中完成所有这些操作。
So you'll be able to train your own very network to drive using real world data.
因此，您将能够使用真实世界数据训练自己的网络。
I'll explain how.  We will also have a tutorial and code.  Briefly described today at the end of the lecture,
我会解释一下。我们还将提供教程和代码。今天在讲座结束时简要介绍，
if there's time how to do the same thing in TensorFlow.
如果有时间如何在TensorFlow中做同样的事情。
So if you want to build a network that's bigger, deeper and you want to utilize GPUs to train that network,
因此，如果您想构建一个更大，更深的网络，并且您希望利用GPU来训练该网络，
you want to not do it in your browser, you want to do it offline using TensorFlow
如果您不想在浏览器中执行此操作，则需要使用TensorFlow离线执行此操作
and having a powerful GPU on your computer and we'll explain how to do that. Computer vision.
并且在您的计算机上拥有强大的GPU，我们将解释如何做到这一点。计算机视觉。
So we talked about vanilla machine learning where there's no-  Where the size, yesterday,
所以我们谈到了香草机器学习哪里没有 - 昨天的大小，
where the size of the input is small for the most part.
其中输入的大小在很大程度上是小的。
The number of neurons, in the case the neural networks, is on the order of 10, 100, 1,000.
在神经网络的情况下，神经元的数量大约为10,100,1,000。
When you think of images, images are a collection of pixels, one of the most iconic images from computer vision
当您想到图像时，图像是像素的集合，是计算机视觉中最具代表性的图像之一
on the bottom left there is Lenna.
在左下方有Lenna。
I encourage you to Google it and figure out the story behind that image.  It's quite shocking when I found out recently.
我鼓励你谷歌它，并找出该图像背后的故事。我最近发现时非常震惊。
So once again, computer vision is, these days, dominated by data driven approaches by machine learning
因此，如今，计算机视觉再次受到机器学习的数据驱动方法的支配
where all of the same methods that are used on other types of data are used on images where the input is just
其中所有与其他类型数据相同的方法都用在输入正好的图像上
a collection of pixels and pixels are numbers from 0  to 255 discrete values.
像素和像素的集合是0到255个离散值的数字。
So we can think exactly what we've talked about previously, you could think of images in the same exact way.  It's just numbers
所以我们可以准确地思考我们之前谈过的内容，你可以用同样的方式来思考图像。这只是数字
and so we can do the same kind of thing.  We could do supervised learning where you have an input image
所以我们可以做同样的事情。我们可以在有输入图像的地方进行监督学习
and output label.  The input image here is a picture of a woman; the label might be "woman".
和输出标签。这里的输入图像是女人的照片;标签可能是“女人”。
On supervised learning, same thing.  We'll look at that briefly as well as clustering images into categories.
关于监督学习，同样的事情。我们将简要地看一下，并将图像聚类到类别中。
Again semi-supervised and reinforcement learning.  In fact, the Atari games that talked about yesterday.
再次半监督和强化学习。事实上，昨天谈到的Atari游戏。
do some pre-processing on the images.  They're doing computer vision;  they're using convolutional neural networks as we'll discuss today
对图像进行一些预处理。他们正在做计算机视觉;他们正在使用卷积神经网络，我们今天将讨论
and the pipeline for supervised learning is again the same:  there's raw data in the form of images,
监督学习的管道也是一样的：有图像形式的原始数据，
there's labels on those images.  We perform a machine learning algorithm, performs feature extraction,
那些图像上有标签。我们执行机器学习算法，执行特征提取，
it trains given the inputs and outputs on the images and the labels of those images, constructs the model
它根据图像的输入和输出以及这些图像的标签进行训练，构建模型
and then test that model.
然后测试该模型。
And we get a metric and accuracy.  Accuracy is the term that's used to often describe how well the model performs.
我们得到了衡量标准和准确性。准确度是用于经常描述模型执行情况的术语。
The percentage.
百分比。
I apologise for the constant presence of cats throughout this course.  I assure you this course is about driving, not cats.
我为整个课程中猫的不断存在而道歉。我向你保证，这个课程是关于驾驶，而不是猫。
but images are numbers.  So for us we take it for granted.
但图像是数字。所以对我们来说，我们认为理所当然。
We're really good at looking
我们真的很擅长看
and converting visual perception as human beings, converting visual perception, into semantics.
将视觉感知转化为人类，将视觉感知转化为语义。
We see this image and we know it's a cat but a computer only sees numbers:  RGB values for a color image.
我们看到这个图像，我们知道它是一只猫，但计算机只能看到数字：彩色图像的RGB值。
There's three values for every single pixel from 0 to 255.
从0到255的每个像素都有三个值。
And so given that image, we can think of two problems:  one is regression and the other is classification.  Regression is when given an image
因此，鉴于该图像，我们可以想到两个问题：一个是回归，另一个是分类。回归是给出一个图像
we want to produce a real value of output put back. So if we have an image of the four roadway,
我们希望产生一个真正的输出值。所以，如果我们有四个车道的图像，
we want to produce a value for the steering wheel angle and if you have an algorithm that's really smart,
我们想要为方向盘角度生成一个值，如果你有一个非常聪明的算法，
It can take any image of the forward roadway
它可以拍摄前方道路的任何图像
and produce the perfectly correct steering angle that drives the car safely across the United States.
并产生完美正确的转向角度，可以安全地驾驶汽车穿越美国。
We'll talk about how to do that and where that fails.  Classification is when the input again is an image
我们将讨论如何做到这一点以及失败的地方。分类是指输入再次是图像
and the output is a class label, a discrete class label.  Underneath it though often is still a regression problem
输出是一个类标签，一个离散的类标签。在它下面虽然经常仍然是一个回归问题
and once produced is a probability that this particular image belongs to a particular category.
并且一旦产生了该特定图像属于特定类别的概率。
And we use a threshold to chop off the outputs associated with low probabilities
我们使用阈值来切断与低概率相关的输出
and take the labels associated with high probabilities and convert it into a discrete classification.
并获取与高概率相关的标签并将其转换为离散分类。
I mentioned this yesterday but it bears saying again, computer vision is hard.
我昨天提到了这个，但它再说一遍，计算机视觉很难。
We, once again, take it for granted.  As human beings, we're really good at dealing with all these problems.
我们再一次认为这是理所当然的。作为人类，我们非常善于处理所有这些问题。
There's viewpoint variation:  the object looks wholly different in terms of the numbers behind the images
存在视点变化：对象在图像背后的数字方面看起来完全不同
in terms of the pixels when viewed from a different angle.
在从不同角度观看时的像素方面。
Viewpoint variation:  objects when you're standing far away from them or up close are totally different size.
视点变化：当您站在远离它们或近距离时的物体尺寸完全不同。
We're good at detecting that there are different size.
我们擅长检测到有不同的尺寸。
It's still the same object as human beings but that's still a really hard problem because those sizes can vary drastically.
它仍然是与人类相同的对象，但这仍然是一个非常难的问题，因为这些尺寸可能会有很大差异。
We talked about occlusions and deformations with cats; well understood problem. There's background clutter.
我们谈到了猫的闭塞和变形;很好理解的问题。有背景杂乱。
You have to separate the object of interest from the background and given the three dimensional structure of our world.
你必须将感兴趣的对象与背景分开，并给出我们世界的三维结构。
There's a lot of stuff often going on in the background:  the clutter, their inter-class variation.
在背景中经常会发生很多事情：混乱，他们的阶级间差异。
That's often greater than inter-class variation; meaning objects of the same type often have more variation
这通常比班级间的变化大;意思是相同类型的对象通常具有更多变化
than the objects that you're trying to separate them from.  There is the hard one for driving:  illumination.
而不是你试图将它们分开的对象。驾驶很难：照明。
Light is the way we perceive things; the reflection of light off the surface
光是我们感知事物的方式;光线从表面反射出来
and the source of that light changes the way that object appears and we have to be robust to all of that.
并且那光的来源改变了对象出现的方式，我们必须对所有这些都很健壮。
So the image classification pipeline is the same as I mentioned.  There are categories,
因此图像分类管道与我提到的相同。有类别，
It's the classification problems for those categories of cat, dog, mug, hat.
这是猫，狗，马克杯，帽子等类别的分类问题。
You have a bunch of examples, image examples of each of those categories
您有一堆示例，每个类别的图像示例
and so the input is just those images paired with the category.
因此输入只是那些与类别配对的图像。
And you train to map, to estimate a function that maps from the images to the categories.
然后你训练地图，估计一个从图像映射到类别的功能。
For all of that you need data; a lot of it.
对于所有这些，您需要数据;很多。
There is, unfortunately, a growing number of data sets but there are still relatively small.
不幸的是，有越来越多的数据集，但仍然相对较小。
We get excited.  There are millions of images but they're not billions or trillions of images and these are,
我们很兴奋。有数百万张图片，但它们不是数十亿或数万亿的图像，这些是，
the data sets that you will see if you read academic literature most often.
如果您最常阅读学术文献，您将看到的数据集。
Mnist, the one that's been beaten to death.
Mnist，一个被打死的人。
And then we use as well in this course the data set of handwritten digits where the categories are 0 to 9.
然后我们在本课程中使用手写数字的数据集，其中类别为0到9。
ImageNet, one of the largest image data sets; fully labeled image data sets in the world has images with a hierarchy of categories from Word Net.
ImageNet，最大的图像数据集之一;世界上完全标记的图像数据集具有来自Word Net的类别层次结构的图像。
And what you see there is a labeling of what image is associated with which words are present in the data set.
您所看到的是标记了哪些图像与数据集中存在的单词相关联。
CIFAR-10 and CIFAR-100 are tiny images that are used to prove in a very efficient and quick way
CIFAR-10和CIFAR-100是微小的图像，用于以非常有效和快速的方式进行验证
offhand that your algorithm that you're trying to publish on, or trying to impress the world with, works well.
你想要发布的算法，或试图给世界留下深刻印象的算法效果很好。
It's small, it's a small data set:  CIFAR-10 means there's 10 categories.
它很小，它是一个小数据集：CIFAR-10意味着有10个类别。
And places is a data set of natural scenes: woods, nature, city, and so on.
地方是自然场景的数据集：森林，自然，城市等。
So let's look at CIFAR-10
那么让我们来看看CIFAR-10
as a data set of 10 categories: airplane, automobile, bird, cat, and so on.
作为10个类别的数据集：飞机，汽车，鸟，猫等。
They're shown there with sample images as the rose.
他们在那里展示了样本图像作为玫瑰。
And so let's build a classifier that's able to take images from one of these 10 categories and tell us what
因此，让我们构建一个分类器，它能够从这10个类别中的一个中获取图像并告诉我们什么
is shown in the image.  So how do we do that?  Once again, all the algorithm sees is numbers.
显示在图像中。那我们怎么做呢？再一次，所有算法都看到了数字。
So we have to try to have at the very core, we have to have an operator for comparing two images.
所以我们必须尝试在核心，我们必须有一个运算符来比较两个图像。
So given an image and I want to save it as a cat or dog.
所以给了一个图像，我想把它保存为猫或狗。
I want to compare it to images of cats and compare it to images of dogs and see which one matches better.
我想将它与猫的图像进行比较，并将其与狗的图像进行比较，看看哪个匹配得更好。
So there has to be a comparative operator.  Okay so one way to do that is take the absolute difference between the two images
所以必须有一个比较运营商。好的，所以一种方法是采取两个图像之间的绝对差异
pixel by pixel, take the difference between
逐个像素，取之间的差异
each individual pixel shown on the bottom of the slide for a 4x4 image.  And then we sum that pixel-wise
幻灯片底部显示的每个像素为4x4图像。然后我们按像素加和
pixel-wise absolute difference into a single number.  So if the image is totally different pixel-wise,
像素方式的绝对差值为单个数字。因此，如果图像在像素方面完全不同，
that will be a high number.
这将是一个很高的数字。
If it's the same image, the number will be 0.  Oh, it's the absolute value too of the difference.
如果它是相同的图像，则数字将为0.哦，这也是差异的绝对值。
And that's called L1 distance.  It doesn't matter.  When we speak of distance, we usually mean L2 distance.
那叫做L1距离。没关系。当我们谈到距离时，我们通常指的是L2距离。
And so, if we try to-  So we can build the classifier that just uses this operator to compare it to every single image in the data set
所以，如果我们尝试 - 所以我们可以构建仅使用此运算符将其与数据集中的每个图像进行比较的分类器
and say I'm going to pick the, I'm going to pick the category
并且说我要选择，我将选择该类别
that's the closest using this comparative operator.  I'm going to find-  I have a picture of a cat
这是使用这个比较运算符的最接近的。我要找 - 我有一张猫的照片
and I'm going to look through the dataset and find the image that's the closest to this picture
我将查看数据集并找到最接近此图片的图像
and say that is the category that this picture belongs to.
并说这是这张照片所属的类别。
So if we just flip the coin and randomly pick which category an image belongs to get that accuracy,
因此，如果我们只是翻转硬币并随机选择图像所属的类别以获得该精度，
would be on average 10%.  It's random.
平均为10％。这是随机的。
The accuracy with which our brilliant image difference algorithm that just goes through the data set
我们精彩的图像差分算法只需经过数据集的准确性
and finds the closest one is 38% which is pretty good, it's way above 10%.
并且发现最接近的是38％这是相当不错的，它超过10％。
So you can think about this operation of look into the base
所以你可以考虑一下这个基础的操作
and finding the closest image as what's called K-Nearest Neighbors
并找到最接近的图像，称为K-Nearest Neighbors
or K in that case.  Meaning you find the one closest neighbor to this image that you're asking questions about
或者在这种情况下为K.这意味着您可以找到与此图像最近的邻居，您正在询问有关的问题
and accept the label from that image.  You could do the same thing increasing K.
并接受该图像的标签。你可以做同样的事情来增加K.
Increasing K to 2 means you take the two nearest neighbors.
将K增加到2表示您选择两个最近的邻居。
You find the two closest in terms of pixel-wise image difference through this particular query image
通过此特定查询图像，您可以找到与像素方式图像差异最接近的两个图像
and find which categories did those belong to.
并找出那些属于哪些类别。
What's shown up top on the left is the data set we're working with:  red, green, blue.
左边显示的是我们正在使用的数据集：红色，绿色，蓝色。
What's shown in the middle is the one nearest neighbor classifier, meaning
中间显示的是最近邻分类器，意思是
this is how you segment the entire space of different things that you can compare.
这就是你如何划分你可以比较的不同事物的整个空间。
And if a point falls into any of these regions,
如果一个点落入这些区域中的任何一个，
it will be immediately associated with the nearest neighbor algorithm to belong to that image, to that region.
它将立即与最近邻居算法相关联，以属于该图像到该区域。
With the five nearest neighbors, there's immediately an issue.  The issue is that there is white regions.
与五个最近的邻居，立即出现问题。问题是有白色区域。
There's tie breakers where your five closest neighbors are from various categories.  So it's unclear where you belong to.
有五个最接近的邻居来自不同类别的领带断路器。所以目前还不清楚你属于哪里。
So this is a good example of parameter tuning.  You have one parameter:  K.
所以这是参数调整的一个很好的例子。你有一个参数：K。
And your task as a teacher of machine learning, you have to teach this algorithm how to do your learning for you,
而你作为机器学习老师的任务，你必须教这个算法如何为你学习，
is to figure out that parameter.
是找出那个参数。
That's called "parameter tuning" or "hyper-parameter tuning" as it's called in neural networks.
这被称为“参数调整”或“超参数调整”，因为它在神经网络中被调用。
And so on the bottom right of the slide on the x-axis is K.  As we increase it from 0 to 100 and
因此，在x轴上滑动的右下角是K.当我们将它从0增加到100时
the y-axis is classification accuracy.  It turns out that the best K for this data set is 7, 7 years neighbors.
y轴是分类精度。事实证明，这个数据集的最佳K是7，7年的邻居。
With that we get a performance of 30% human level performance
通过它，我们获得了30％的人类水平表现
and I should say that the way we get that number as we do with a lot of the machine learning pipeline
而且我应该说我们获得这个数字的方式和我们使用很多机器学习管道一样
process is you separate the data into the parts of days that you use for training
过程是您将数据分成用于培训的天数
and another part they use for testing.  You're not allowed to touch the testing part.  That's cheating.
以及他们用于测试的另一部分。您不能接触测试部件。那是作弊。
You construct your model of the world on the training data set and you use what's called cross validation
您可以在训练数据集上构建您的世界模型，并使用所谓的交叉验证
where you take a small part of the training data shown "fold five" there in yellow to leave that part out from
你把一小部分训练数据显示为“折叠五”，那里是黄色的，留下那部分
the training and then use it as part of the hyper-parameter tuning.  As you train, figure out with that yellow part fold five
训练然后将其用作超参数调整的一部分。当你训练时，弄清楚黄色部分折五
how well you're doing  and then you choose a different fold and see how well you're doing
你做得多好，然后你选择一个不同的折叠，看看你做得多好
And keep playing with parameters never touching the test part.  And when you're ready,
并继续使用从未接触测试部件的参数。当你准备好了，
you run the algorithm on a test data to see how well you really do.  How will it really generalizes.  Yes, question.
您在测试数据上运行算法，看看您的真实情况。它将如何真正概括。是的，问题。
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
So, the question was:  "is there a good way to-
所以，问题是：“有没有好办法 -
Is any good intuition behind what a good K is?"  There are general rules for different data sets
好的K背后有什么好的直觉吗？“对于不同的数据集有一般规则
but usually you just have to run through it.  Grid search, brute force.  Yes, question.
但通常你只需要经历它。网格搜索，蛮力。是的，问题。
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
(CHUCKLING)
（笑着）
Good question.  Yes.
好问题。是。
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
Yes, the question was:  "is each pixel 1 number or 3 numbers?"
是的，问题是：“每个像素是1个数字还是3个数字？”
For majority of computer vision throughout its history used grayscale images so it's 1 number but RGB
对于整个历史记录中的大多数计算机视觉使用灰度图像，因此它是1个数字但RGB
is 3 numbers and there's sometimes a depth value too, so it's 4 numbers. So it's-
是3个数字，有时也有深度值，所以它是4个数字。所以这是-
If you have a stereo vision camera that gives you the depth information of the pixels,
如果您有立体视觉相机，可以为您提供像素的深度信息，
that's a fourth and then if you stack two images together there could be 6.  In general,
这是第四个然后如果你把两个图像堆叠在一起可能是6.一般来说，
everything we work with will be 3 numbers for a pixel.
我们使用的所有内容都是一个像素的3个数字。
Yes, so the question:  "as to the absolute value is just one number?"
是的，所以问题是：“关于绝对值只是一个数字？”
Exactly right.  So in that case, those are grayscale images.
非常正确。那么在那种情况下，那些是灰度图像。
So it's not RGB images.
所以这不是RGB图像。
So, you know, this algorithm is pretty good if we use the best.
所以，你知道，如果我们使用最好的算法，这个算法非常好。
We optimize the hyper-parameters of this algorithm, choose K of 7,
我们优化了这个算法的超参数，选择K为7，
seems to work well for this particular CIFAR-10 data set.  Okay, we get 30% accuracy.
似乎适用于这个特定的CIFAR-10数据集。好的，我们得到30％的准确率。
It's impressive, higher than 10%.  Human beings perform at about 94, slightly above 94%
它令人印象深刻，高于10％。人类的表现约为94，略高于94％
accuracy for CIFAR-10.  So given an image and it's a tiny image.  I should clarify it, it's like a little icon.
CIFAR-10的准确度。所以给定一个图像，这是一个很小的图像。我应该澄清一下，它就像一个小图标。
Given that image, human beings are able to determine accurately one of the 10 categories with 94% accuracy.
鉴于该图像，人类能够准确地确定10个类别中的一个，准确率为94％。
And the currently state-of-the-art convolutional neural networks is ninety five,
目前最先进的卷积神经网络是九十五，
it's 95.4% accuracy and, believe it or not, it's a heated battle
这是95.4％的准确度，不管你信不信，这是一场激烈的战斗
but the most important, the critical fact here, is it's recently surpassed humans.
但最重要的是，这里的关键事实是，它最近超越了人类。
And certainly surpass the k-nearest neighbors algorithm.  So,how does this work?  Let's briefly look back.
并且肯定超过k近邻算法。那么，这是如何工作的？让我们简要回顾一下。
It all still boils down to this little guy:  the neuron,
这一切仍然归结为这个小家伙：神经元，
that sums the weights of its inputs, adds a bias, produces an output based on an activation, a smooth activation function.
它将输入的权重相加，增加偏差，根据激活产生输出，平滑激活函数。
Yes, question.
是的，问题。
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
The question was:  "do you take a picture of Cassie, you know it's a cat,
问题是：“你拍摄卡西的照片，你知道它是一只猫，
but that's not encoded anywhere, like you have to write that down somewhere.
但这并没有在任何地方编码，就像你必须把它写在某处。
So you have to write as a caption:  "This is my cat."
所以你必须写一个标题：“这是我的猫。”
And then the unfortunate thing, given the internet and how woody it is, you can't trust the captions on images.
然后不幸的是，鉴于互联网和它是多么木质，你不能相信图像上的字幕。
because maybe you're just being clever and it's not a cat all, it's a dog dressed as a cat.  Yes, question.
因为也许你只是聪明而且它不是一只猫，它是一只装扮成猫的狗。是的，问题。
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
Sorry.  Seen as do better than what?
抱歉。看得更好比什么？
Yes, so the question was:  "do convolutional neural networks generally do better than nearest neighbors?
是的，所以问题是：“卷积神经网络通常比最近的邻居做得好吗？
There's very few problems on which neural networks don't do better, yes ,they almost always do better
神经网络没有做得更好的问题很少，是的，它们几乎总能做得更好
except when you have almost no data.  So you need data.  And convolutional neural networks isn't some special magical thing.
除非您几乎没有数据。所以你需要数据。而卷积神经网络并不是一些特殊的神奇之物。
It's just neural networks with some cheating up front that I'll explain, some tricks to try to reduce the size
这只是神经网络，前面有一些作弊，我会解释，尝试减小尺寸的一些技巧
and make it capable to deal with images.
并使其能够处理图像。
So again.  Yes, the input is, in this case that we looked at classifying an image of a number,
再说一遍。是的，输入是，在这种情况下，我们考虑分类数字的图像，
as opposed to doing some fancy convolutional tricks.  We just take the the entire 28x28
而不是做一些花哨的卷积技巧。我们只需要整个28x28
pixel image that's 784 pixels as the input.
像素图像为784像素作为输入。
That's 784 neurons in the input, 15 neurons on the hidden layer and 10 neurons in the output.
那是输入中的784个神经元，隐藏层上的15个神经元和输出中的10个神经元。
Now everything we'll talk about has the same exact structure.  Nothing fancy.
现在我们要讨论的一切都具有相同的结构。没有什么花哨。
There is a forward pass through the network where you take an input image and produce an output classification
有一个正向传递通过网络，您可以在其中获取输入图像并生成输出分类
and there's a backward pass through the network for Back Propagation where you adjust the weights
并且有一个向后传递通过网络进行反向传播，您可以在其中调整权重
when your prediction doesn't match the Ground Truth output.
当您的预测与地面真相输出不匹配时。
And learning just boils down to optimization; it's just optimizing a smooth function.
学习只是归结为优化;它只是优化平滑功能。
Differentiable function; that's defined as the lost function.
功能差异化;这被定义为丢失的功能。
That's usually as simple as a squared error between the true output
这通常就像真实输出之间的平方误差一样简单
and the one you actually got.  So what's the difference?  What are convolutional neural networks?
而你实际得到的那个。那有什么区别？什么是卷积神经网络？
Convolutional neural networks take inputs that have some spatial consistency, have some meaning to the spatial-
卷积神经网络采用具有一定空间一致性的输入，对空间具有一定的意义 -
Has some spatial meaning in them like images.  There's other things, you can think of the dimension of time.
它们具有一些空间意义，如图像。还有其他的东西，你可以想到时间的维度。
And you can input audio signal into a convolutional neural network.  And so the input is, usually for every single layer,
您可以将音频信号输入卷积神经网络。所以输入通常是针对每一层，
that's a convolutional layer, the input is a 3D volume and the output is a 3D volume.
这是一个卷积层，输入是一个3D体积，输出是一个3D体积。
I'm simplifying because you can call it 4D too but it's 3D.  There's height, width and depth.
我正在简化，因为你可以称之为4D但它是3D。有高度，宽度和深度。
So that's an image.  The height and the width is the width and the height of the image.
这是一张图片。高度和宽度是图像的宽度和高度。
And then the depth for grayscale image is 1; for an RGB image is 3;
然后灰度图像的深度为1;对于RGB图像是3;
for a ten-frame video of greyscale images the depth is 10.
对于灰度图像的十帧视频，深度为10。
It's just a volume, a three-dimensional matrix of numbers.  And everything-
它只是一个体积，一个三维的数字矩阵。和所有-
The only thing that a convolutional layer does is take a 3D volume's input, produce a 3D volume as output
卷积层唯一能做的就是获取3D体积的输入，生成3D体积作为输出
and has some smooth function.
并具有一些平滑的功能。
Operating on the inputs, on the sum of the inputs,
在输入上操作，输入总和，
that may or may not be a parameter that you tune, that you try to optimize.  That's it.
您尝试优化的可能是也可能不是您调整的参数。而已。
So Lego pieces that you stack together in the same way as we talked about before.
所以Lego的碎片就像我们之前谈到的那样堆叠在一起。
So what are the types of layers that a convolutional neural networks have?  There's inputs.
那么卷积神经网络有哪些层次类型？有投入。
So for example a color image of 32x32 will be a volume of 32x32x3.
因此，例如32x32的彩色图像将是32x32x3的体积。
A convolutional layer takes advantage of the spatial relationships of the input neurons and a convolutional layer,
卷积层利用输入神经元和卷积层的空间关系，
it's the same exact neuron
它是完全相同的神经元
as for fully connected network, the regular we talked about before.
至于完全连接的网络，我们之前谈过的常规。
But it has a narrower receptive field, it's more focused, the inputs to a neuron on the convolutional layer
但它有一个较窄的感受野，它更集中，是卷积层神经元的输入
come from a specific region from the previous layer.  And the parameters
来自前一层的特定区域。和参数
on each filter, you can think of this as a filter, because you slide it across the entire image.
在每个过滤器上，您可以将其视为过滤器，因为您将其滑过整个图像。
And those parameters are shared.  So supposed you've taken the-  If you think about two layers,
这些参数是共享的。所以假设你已经采取了 - 如果你考虑两层，
as opposed to connecting every single pixel in the first layer to every single neuron in the following layer.
而不是将第一层中的每个像素连接到下一层中的每个单个神经元。
You only connect the neurons in the input layer that are close to each other, to the output layer, and then you
您只需将输入层中彼此接近的神经元连接到输出层，然后再连接到您
enforce the weights to be tied together spatially.
强制权重在空间上捆绑在一起。
And what that results in is a filter every single layer on the output,
结果是输出上的每一层过滤器，
you can think of as a filter, they get excited for example for an edge
你可以把它想象成一个过滤器，他们会因为边缘而感到兴奋
and when it sees this particular kind of edge in the image, it will get excited.
当它在图像中看到这种特殊的边缘时，它会变得兴奋。
And it'll get excited in the top left of the image, on the top right, bottom left, bottom right.
而且它会在图像的左上角，右上角，左下角，右下角激动。
The assumption there is that a powerful feature for detecting a cat
假设有一个检测猫的强大功能
is just as important no matter where in the image it is.
无论图像在哪里，它都同样重要。
And this allows you to cut away a huge number of connections between neurons but it still boils down on the right,
这可以让你切断神经元之间的大量连接，但它仍然在右边，
as a neuron that sums a collection of inputs
作为总结输入集合的神经元
and applies weights to them.  The spatial arrangement of the output volume relative to the input volume
并对它们施加权重。输出音量相对于输入音量的空间排列
is controlled by three things.  The number of filters.  So for every single "filter"
由三件事控制。过滤器的数量。所以对于每一个“过滤器”
you get an extra layer on the output.  So if the input,
你在输出上得到一个额外的图层。所以如果输入，
let's talk about the very first layer, the input is 32x32x3.  It's in RGB
让我们来谈谈第一层，输入是32x32x3。它是RGB
image of 32x32.  If the number of filters is 10,
32x32的图像。如果过滤器的数量是10，
then the resulting depth the resulting number of stacked channels in the output will be 10.  Stride is given.
然后得到的深度，输出中产生的堆叠通道数将为10.给出了步幅。
is the step size of the filter that you slide along the image.  Often times as just 1 or 3
是您沿图像滑动的滤镜的步长。通常只有1或3
and that directly reduces the size, the spatial size the width and the height, of the output image.
这直接减小了输出图像的大小，空间大小，宽度和高度。
and then there is a convenient thing that it's often done is padding.  The image on the outside zeros.
然后有一个方便的事情，它经常做填充。外面的零上的图像。
So that the input and the output have the same height and width.  So this is a visualization of convolution.
这样输入和输出具有相同的高度和宽度。所以这是卷积的可视化。
I encourage you to, kind of maybe offline, think about what's happening.
我鼓励你，有点离线，想想发生了什么。
It's similar to the way human vision works, crudely so, if there's any experts in the audience.
它与人类视觉的工作方式类似，粗略地说，如果观众中有任何专家。
So the input here on the left is a collection of numbers:  0, 1, 2.  And a filter
所以左边的输入是一组数字：0,1,2和一个过滤器
or there are two filters shown as W1-
或者有两个过滤器显示为W1-
W0 and W1.  Those filters shown in red, are the different weights applied in those filters.
W0和W1。以红色显示的那些过滤器是在这些过滤器中应用的不同权重。
And each of the filters have a certain depth; just like the input a depth of 3.
并且每个滤波器都有一定的深度;就像输入深度为3。
So there are three of them in each column and so,
所以每列中有三个，所以，
so you slide death filter along the image keeping the weights the same.
所以你沿着图像滑动死亡过滤器，保持重量相同。
this is the sharing of the weights
这是权重的共享
and so your first filter you pick the weights, this is an optimization problem. you pick the weights in such a way
所以你选择权重的第一个过滤器，这是一个优化问题。你以这种方式挑选权重
that it fires, it gets excited, for useful features and doesn't fire for not useful features.
它会激发，它会变得兴奋，因为有用的功能而且不会因为没有用的功能而激发。
And then there's a second filter that fires for useful features and not.
然后有第二个过滤器可以激发有用的功能，而不是。
And produces a signal on the output depending on a positive number, meaning there's a strong feature in that region,
并根据正数在输出上产生一个信号，这意味着该区域有一个强大的特征，
and negative number if there isn't but the filter is the same.
如果没有，则为负数，但过滤器相同。
This allows for a drastic reduction in the parameters and so you can deal with
这样可以大大减少参数，因此您可以处理
inputs.  There are a thousand by thousand pixel image, for example, or video. There's a really powerful concept there.
投入。例如，有一千个像素的图像或视频。那里有一个非常强大的概念。
The spatial sharing of weights.
权重的空间共享。
That means there's a spatial invariance to the features you're detecting.  It allows you to learn from arbitrary images
这意味着您正在检测的功能存在空间不变性。它允许您从任意图像中学习
so you don't have to be concerned about pre-processing the images in some clever way,
所以你不必担心以一种聪明的方式预处理图像，
you just give the raw image.  There is another operation:  pooling.
你只需要提供原始图像。还有另一个操作：汇集。
It's a way to reduce the size of the layers by, for example in this case,
这是一种减少图层大小的方法，例如在这种情况下，
it's max pooling for taking a collection of outputs and choose x1
它是获取输出集合并选择x1的最大池
and summarizing those collection of pixels such that the output of the pooling operation is much smaller than the input.
并总结那些像素集合，使得池化操作的输出远小于输入。
Because the justification there is that you don't need a high resolution.
因为有理由认为你不需要高分辨率。
Localization of which pixel is important in the image or according to, you know,
根据您所知，图像中的哪个像素的本地化很重要
you don't need to know exactly which pixel is associated with the cat ear or a cat face.
您不需要确切知道哪个像素与猫耳或猫脸相关联。
As long as you, kind of, know it's around that part
只要你，那种，知道它就是那个部分
and that reduces a lot of complexity in the operations. Yes, question.
这减少了操作中的大量复杂性。是的，问题。
The question was:  "when is too much pooling, when do you stop pooling?"
问题是：“什么时候汇集太多，什么时候停止汇集？”
So pooling is a very crude operation that doesn't have any, one thing you need to know, is it doesn't have any
所以汇集是一个非常粗糙的操作，没有任何东西，你需要知道的一件事，它没有任何东西
parameters that are learnable.
可学习的参数。
So you can't learn anything clever about pooling.  You're just picking, in this case
所以你无法学到任何关于汇集的聪明之处。在这种情况下，你只是选择
max pool, so you're picking the largest number.  So you're reducing the resolution, you're losing a lot of information.
max pool，所以你选的是最大的数字。所以你降低了分辨率，你丢失了很多信息。
There's an argument that you're not, you know, losing that much information as long as you're not pooling the entire
有一种观点认为，只要你没有把整个信息汇集起来，你就不会丢失那么多信息
image into a single value
将图像转换为单个值
but you're gaining training efficiency, you're gaining the memory size, reducing the size of the network.
但是你获得了培训效率，你正在获得内存大小，减少了网络的规模。
So, it's definitely a thing that people debate and it's a parameter that you play with to see what works for you.
所以，这绝对是人们争论的事情，它是你玩的参数，看看什么对你有用。
Okay, so how does this thing look like as a whole, a convolutional neural network, the input is an image
好吧，那么这个东西整体来说是一个卷积神经网络，输入是一个图像
there's usually a convolutional layer, there is a pooling operation, another convolutional layer, another pooling operation and so on.
通常有一个卷积层，有一个池操作，另一个卷积层，另一个池操作等等。
At the very end, if the task is classification you have a stack of convolutional layers and pooling layers.
最后，如果任务是分类，则会有一堆卷积层和池化层。
There are several fully connected layers.
有几个完全连接的层。
So, you go from those spatial convolutional operations to fully connecting every single neuron in a layer to the
因此，您可以从那些空间卷积操作中完全连接图层中的每个神经元
following layer.
以下层。
And you do this so that by the end, you have a collection of neurons each one is associated with a particular class.
并且你这样做，以便最终，你有一组神经元，每个神经元都与一个特定的类相关联。
So in what we looked at yesterday is the input, is an image of a number 0 through 9.
所以我们昨天看到的是输入，是一个0到9的图像。
The output here would be 10  neurons. So you blow down that image with a collection of convolutional layers,
这里的输出将是10个神经元。所以你用一组卷积层来吹倒那个图像，
with 1 or 2 or 3 fully connected layers at the end that all lead to 10 neurons
在末端有1或2或3个完全连接的层，所有层都导致10个神经元
and each of those neuron's job is to get fired up
而且每个神经元的工作都要被解雇
when it sees a particular number and for the other ones to produce a low probability.  And so this kind of process
当它看到一个特定的数字，而其他的则产生一个低概率。所以这种过程
is how you have the 95 percentile accuracy on the CIFAR-10 problem.
是如何在CIFAR-10问题上获得95％的精确度。
This here is ImageNet data set that I mentioned.  It's how you take this image of a leopard, of a container ship,
这是我提到的ImageNet数据集。这就是你如何拍摄豹子，集装箱船的形象，
and produce a probability that that is a container ship or a leopard.
并产生一个集装箱船或豹子的可能性。
Also shown there are the outputs of the other nearest neurons in terms of their confidence.
还显示了在其置信度方面存在其他最近神经元的输出。
Now you can use the same exact operation by chopping off the fully connected layer at the end
现在，您可以通过在末端切断完全连接的层来使用相同的精确操作
and as opposed to mapping from image to a prediction of what's contained in the image, you map from the image to another image.
而不是从图像映射到图像中包含的内容的预测，您将从图像映射到另一个图像。
And you can train that image to be one that gets excited
而且你可以训练那个令人兴奋的形象
spatially, meaning it gives you a high, close to one value, for areas of the image that contain the object of interest
在空间上，意味着它为包含感兴趣对象的图像区域提供高，接近一个值
and then a low number for areas of the image that are unlikely to contain that image.
然后是不太可能包含该图像的图像区域的低数字。
And so from this you can go on the left,
所以你可以从左边开始，
an original image of a woman on a horse, to a segmented image of knowing where the woman is and where the horse is
马的女人的原始图像，知道女人在哪里以及马在哪里的分段图像
and where the background is.  The same process can be done for detecting the object.
以及背景的位置。可以进行相同的过程来检测对象。
So you can segment the scene into a bunch of
所以你可以把场景分成几堆
interesting objects, candidates for interesting objects and then go through those candidates one by one
有趣的对象，有趣的对象的候选人，然后逐个审查这些候选人
and perform the same kind of classification as in the previous step where it's just an input as an image and the output as a classification.
并执行与上一步骤相同的分类，其中它只是作为图像的输入和作为分类的输出。
And through this process of hopping around an image, you can figure out exactly where is the best way to segment the cow
通过这个跳过图像的过程，你可以准确地找出分割牛的最佳方法
out of the image.  That's called object detection.  Okay, so
出于图像。这就是所谓的物体检测。可以，然后呢
how can these magical convolutional neural networks help us in driving?  This is a video of the forward road way from a
这些神奇的卷积神经网络如何帮助我们驾驶？这是一个前进道路的视频
data set that we'll look at, that we've collected from a Tesla.  But first let me look at driving.
我们将看到的数据集，我们从特斯拉收集的数据集。但首先让我看一下驾驶。
Briefly, the general driving task from the human perspective.  On average an American driver in the United States
简而言之，从人的角度来看一般的驾驶任务。平均而言是美国的一名美国司机
drives 10,000 miles a year.  A little more for rural, a little less for urban.  There is about 30,000
每年驾驶10,000英里。农村多一点，城市少一点。大约有30,000人
fatal crashes and >32,000 sometimes as high as 38,000 fatalities a year.
致命的撞车事故，每年有32,000人死亡，有时高达38,000人死亡。
This includes car occupants, pedestrians, bicyclists and motorcycle riders.
这包括汽车乘客，行人，骑自行车者和摩托车骑手。
This may be a surprising fact but in a class on self-driving cars we should remember that.
这可能是一个令人惊讶的事实，但在自驾车的课堂上我们应该记住这一点。
So ignore the 59.9%, that's other.  The most popular cars in the United States are pickup trucks:  Ford F-1 Series,
所以忽略59.9％，那是另一个。美国最受欢迎的汽车是皮卡车：福特F-1系列，
Chevy Silverado, Ram.  It's an important point that we're still married to our,
Ram，雪佛兰Silverado。重要的一点是，我们仍然嫁给了我们，
to wanting to be in control and so one of the interesting cars that we look at
想要控制，所以我们看到的有趣的汽车之一
and the car that is the days that we provide to the class is collected from is a Tesla.
从特斯拉那里收集我们提供给班级的日子。
It's the one that comes at the intersection of the Ford F-150
这是福特F-150的交叉点
and the cute, little Google self-driving car on the right.  It's fast, it allows you to have a feeling of control
和右边可爱的小型自动驾驶汽车。它很快，它让你有一种控制感
but it can also drive itself for hundreds of miles on the highway, if need be.
但如果需要的话，它也可以在高速公路上行驶数百英里。
It allows you to press a button and the car takes over.
它允许您按下按钮，汽车接管。
It's a fascinating trade-off, of transferring control from the human to the car.
将控制从人类转移到汽车是一种非常有趣的权衡。
It's a transfer of trust
这是一种信任转移
and it's a chance for us to study the psychology of human beings as they relate to machines at >60 miles an hour.
这是我们研究人类心理的一个机会，因为它们与每小时60英里以上的机器有关。
In case you're not aware a little summary of human beings, where distracted things:  would like to text, use the smartphone,
万一你不知道人类的一点点总结，分心的事情：想要发短信，使用智能手机，
watch videos, groom, talk to passengers, eat, drink, texting.
观看视频，新郎，与乘客交谈，吃饭，喝酒，发短信。
169 billion texts were sent in the US every single month in 2014.
2014年，美国每个月都发送了1690亿条文本。
On average, 5 seconds our eyes spent off the road while texting -  5 seconds.
平均而言，我们的眼睛在发短信时花了5秒钟 -  5秒钟。
That's the opportunity for automation to step in.  More than that, there's what NHTSA refers to as the 4 D's:  drunk, drugged,
这是自动化介入的机会。更重要的是，NHTSA称之为4 D：醉酒，吸毒，
distracted and drowsy.
心烦意乱，昏昏欲睡。
Each one of those opportunity is for automation to step in.  Drunk driving stands to benefit significantly
这些机会中的每一个都是为了让自动化步入。醉酒驾驶显着受益
from automation, perhaps.  So the miles, let's look at the miles.  The data.  There's 3 trillion (3 million million)
或许来自自动化。所以英里，让我们看看里程。数据。有3万亿（300万）
3 million million miles driven every year and TESLA autopilot, our case study for this class,
每年驾驶300万英里和TESLA自动驾驶仪，我们的课程研究，
and as human beings is driven on full auto-pilot mode.
并且人类在完全自动驾驶模式下驾驶。
So it's driving by itself 300 million miles as of December 2016
因此，截至2016年12月，它自行驾驶3亿英里
and the fatalities for human control vehicles is 1:90,000,000.
而人类控制车辆的死亡人数为1：90,000,000。
It's about >30,000 fatalities a year and currently under TESLA auto-pilot there's one fatality.
每年约有30,000人死亡，目前在TESLA自动驾驶仪下有一人死亡。
There's a lot of ways you could tear that statistic apart but it's one to think about.  Already, perhaps automation
你可以通过很多方式撕掉这个统计数据，但这是一个值得考虑的方法。已经，也许是自动化
results in safer driving.  The thing is, we don't understand automation,
导致更安全的驾驶。问题是，我们不了解自动化，
because we don't have the data:  we don't have the data on the forward roadway video, we don't have the data on the driver
因为我们没有数据：我们没有关于前进道路视频的数据，我们没有关于驱动程序的数据
and we just don't have that many cars on the road today that drive themselves.  So we need a lot of data.
而我们今天在路上没有那么多自行驾驶的汽车。所以我们需要大量的数据。
We'll provide some of it to you in the class and as part of our research at MIT were collecting huge amounts of it,
我们将在课堂上为您提供部分内容，作为麻省理工学院研究的一部分，我们正在收集大量的内容，
of cars driving themselves, and collecting that data is how we get to understanding.
汽车驾驶自己，收集数据是我们理解的方式。
So talking about the data and what we'll be doing training our algorithms on, here is a Tesla Model S, Model X
所以谈论数据以及我们将要对我们的算法进行训练的内容，这里是特斯拉模型S，模型X.
we've instrumented 17 of them, have collected over 5,000 hours and 70,000 miles.
我们已经对其中的17个进行了检测，已经收集了超过5,000小时和70,000英里。
And I'll talk about the cameras that we've put in them.  We're collecting video of the forward road way.
我会谈谈我们放入它们的相机。我们正在收集前进道路的视频。
This is a highlight of a trip from Boston to Florida of one of the people driving a Tesla.  What's also shown in blue is the
这是从波士顿到佛罗里达的一个驾驶特斯拉的人的一个亮点。什么也用蓝色显示是
amount of time that autopilot was engaged:  currently 0 minutes and then it grows and grows.
自动驾驶仪使用的时间：目前为0分钟，然后它会增长和增长。
For prolonged periods of time, so hundreds of miles, people engage autopilot.  Out of 1.3 billion
长时间，如此数百英里，人们使用自动驾驶仪。超过13亿
miles driven a Tesla, 300,000,000 are on autopilot.  You do the math whatever that is, 25%.
英特尔驾驶特斯拉，300,000,000正在自动驾驶。无论如何你做数学，25％。
So we are collecting data of the forward roadway, of the driver.  We have 2 cameras on the driver.
所以我们正在收集司机前方道路的数据。我们在驱动程序上有2个摄像头。
What we're providing with the class is epics of time of the forward roadway, for privacy considerations.  Cameras used
出于隐私考虑，我们提供的课程是前进道路的时间史诗。使用相机
to record are your regular Webcam, the work horse of the computer vision community.  The C920,
记录是你的常规网络摄像头，计算机视觉社区的工作马。 C920，
and we have some special lenses on top of it.
我们在它上面有一些特殊的镜头。
Now what's special about these webcams?  Nothing that costs $70 can be that good, right?
现在这些网络摄像头有什么特别之处？没花70美元可以那么好，对吧？
What's special about them is that they do onboard compression and allow you to collect huge amounts of data
它们的特殊之处在于它们可以进行板载压缩并允许您收集大量数据
and use reasonably sized storage capacity to store that data and train your algorithms on.
并使用合理大小的存储容量来存储数据并训练您的算法。
So what on the self-driving side do we have to work with?  How do we build a self-driving car?
那么在自动驾驶方面我们必须与之合作？我们如何建造一辆自动驾驶汽车？
There is these sensors:  radar, lidar, vision,
有这些传感器：雷达，激光雷达，视觉，
audio - all looking outside helping you detect the objects in the external environment to localize yourself and so on.
音频 - 所有外观都可以帮助您检测外部环境中的对象以自行定位等等。
And there's the sensors facing inside:  visible light camera, audio again,
面向内部的传感器：可见光摄像头，再次音频，
and infrared camera to help detect peoples.
和红外摄像头，以帮助检测人民。
So we can decompose the self-driving car task into 4 steps:  localization, answering where am I; scene understanding,
因此，我们可以将自动驾驶汽车任务分解为4个步骤：本地化，回答我在哪里;场景理解，
using the texture of the information of the scene around, to interpret the identity of the different objects in the
使用周围场景信息的纹理，来解释中不同对象的身份
scene and the semantic meaning of those objects, of their movement.
场景和那些物体的语义，它们的运动。
There's movement planning - once you figured all that out, found all the pedestrians, found all the other cars,
有运动计划 - 一旦你想到这一切，发现所有的行人，发现所有其他车，
how do I navigate through this maze, a clutter of objects in a safe and legal way.  And there's driver state,
我如何以安全合法的方式浏览这个迷宫，一堆杂物。还有司机状态，
how do I detect using video or other information.
如何使用视频或其他信息进行检测。
The video of the driver detect information about their emotional state or their distraction level.  Yes, question.
驾驶员的视频检测有关他们的情绪状态或他们的分心程度的信息。是的，问题。
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
Yes, that's the real-time figure from lidar.  Lidars are sensors that provides you the 3D point cloud
是的，这是激光雷达的实时数字。激光雷达是为您提供3D点云的传感器
of the external scene.  So lidar is the technology used by
外部场景。所以激光雷达是使用的技术
most folks working with self-driving cars to give you a strong Ground Truth of the objects.  It's probably the best sensor we have
大多数人使用自动驾驶汽车为您提供物体的强大地面真相。它可能是我们拥有的最好的传感器
for getting 3D information, the least noisy 3D information about the external environment.  Question.
获取3D信息，关于外部环境的3D信息最少。题。
So autopilot is always changing.  One of the most amazing things about this vehicle is that the updates to autopilot come in
所以自动驾驶仪总是在变化。关于这款车的最令人惊奇的事情之一是自动驾驶仪的更新进来了
the form of software.
软件的形式。
So the amount of time it's available to changes has become more conservative with time.
因此，随着时间的推移，可用于更改的时间变得更加保守。
But in this, this one of the earlier versions,
但在此，这是早期版本之一，
and it shows, the second line in yellow, shows how often autopilot was available but not turned on.
并且它显示，黄色的第二行显示自动驾驶仪可用但未开启的频率。
So the total driving time was 10 hours, autopilot was available 7 hours and was engaged an hour.
因此，总驾驶时间为10小时，自动驾驶仪可用7小时，并且需要一小时。
This particular person is a responsible driver because what you see or
这个特别的人是一个负责任的司机，因为你看到或
is a more cautious driver.  What you see is it's raining, autopilot is still available
是一个更谨慎的司机。你看到的是下雨，自动驾驶仪仍然可用
but-
但-
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
the comment was that you shouldn't trust that one fatality number as an indication of safety because the drivers
评论是你不应该相信那个死亡人数作为安全的指示，因为司机
elect to only engage the system when it's safe to do so.  It's a totally open,
选择只在安全的情况下参与系统。这是完全开放的，
there's a lot bigger arguments for that number than just that one, the question is whether that's a bad
对于那个数字而言，有一个更大的论点而不仅仅是那一个，问题是这是否是一个坏的
thing so maybe we can trust human beings to engage, you know,
所以也许我们可以信任人类参与，你知道，
despite the poorly filmed YouTube videos, despite the hype in the media, you're still a human being.
尽管YouTube视频播放效果不佳，尽管媒体大肆炒作，但你仍然是一个人。
riding 60 miles an hour in a metal box with your life on the line.
乘坐金属盒每小时60英里，生活就行了。
You won't engage the system unless you know it's completely safe unless you've built up a relationship with it.
除非您知道系统完全安全，否则您不会参与系统，除非您与系统建立了关系。
It's not all the stuff you see where a person gets in the back of a Tesla and start sleeping or is playing chess,
这并不是你看到一个人在特斯拉后面开始睡觉或下棋的所有东西，
or whatever.  That's all for YouTube, the reality is when it's just you in the car
管他呢。这就是YouTube的全部内容，现实情况是，只有你在车里
it's still your life on the line and so you're going to do the responsible thing unless perhaps you're a teenager
它仍然是你的生活，所以你要做负责任的事情，除非你是一个少年
and so on but that never changes no matter what you're in.
等等，但无论你在什么地方，都不会改变。
Question.
题。
(INAUDIBLE QUESTION)
（不可思议的问题）
The question was:  "what do you need to see
问题是：“你需要看什么？
or sense about the external environment to be able to successfully drive?  Do you need lane markings?  Do you need other-
或感觉外部环境能够成功驾驶？你需要车道标记吗？你还需要其他 -
what are the landmarks based on which you do the localization and navigation?"
您根据哪些地标进行本地化和导航？“
And that depends on the sensors.  So with the Google self-driving car in sunny California,
这取决于传感器。因此，在阳光明媚的加利福尼亚州使用Google自动驾驶汽车
it depends on lidar in a high-resolution way, map the environment in order to be able to localize itself
它以高分辨率的方式依赖激光雷达，映射环境以便能够本地化
based on lidar.  And lidar, now I don't know the details of exactly where lidar fails,
基于激光雷达。和激光雷达，现在我不知道激光雷达失效的具体细节，
but it's not good with rain, it's not good with snow, it's not good
但是下雨不好，雪也不好，不好
when the environment is changing.  So what snow does is it changes the visual, the appearance, the reflective texture
当环境发生变化时。所以雪是什么，它改变了视觉，外观，反射纹理
of the surfaces around.  Us human beings are still able to figure stuff out
周围的表面。我们人类仍然能够解决问题
but a car that's relying heavily on lidar won't be able to localize itself using the landmarks
但是一辆严重依赖激光雷达的汽车将无法使用这些地标进行本地化
it previously has detected because they look different
它以前检测到，因为它们看起来不同
now with the snow.  Computer vision can help us with lanes
现在有了雪。计算机视觉可以帮助我们使用车道
or following a car.  The two landmarks that we used in a lane is following the car in front of you
或者跟着一辆车。我们在车道上使用的两个地标跟随着你前面的车
or staying between two lanes.  That's the nice thing about our roadways it's they're designed for human eyes.
或者呆在两条车道之间。这对我们的道路来说是件好事，因为它们是为人眼设计的。
So you can use computer vision for lanes and for cars in front to follow them. And there is radar.
因此，您可以使用计算机视觉用于车道和前方车辆跟随它们。还有雷达。
That's a crude but a reliable source of distance information that allows you to not collide with metal objects.
这是一个原始但可靠的距离信息来源，可以让你不与金属物体碰撞。
So all that together depending on what you want to rely on more gives you a lot of information.
因此，根据您想要依赖的内容，所有这些共同为您提供了大量信息。
The question is when its messy complexity of real life occurs,
问题是当现实生活的混乱发生时，
how reliable it would be in the urban environment and so on.  So localization-  How can deep learning help?
它在城市环境中的可靠性等等。本地化 - 深度学习如何帮助？
So first, just a quick summary of visual odometry.  It's using a monocular or stereo input of video images
首先，只是视觉测距的快速总结。它使用视频图像的单眼或立体声输入
to determine your orientation in the world.  The orientation, in this case, of a vehicle in the frame of the world
确定你在世界上的方向。在这种情况下，在世界框架中的车辆的方向
and all you have to work with is a video of the forward roadway
而你所要处理的只是前进道路的视频
and with stereo you get a little extra information of how far away different objects are.
通过立体声，您可以获得有关不同物体有多远的额外信息。
And so this is where one of our speakers on Friday will talk about his expertise (SLAM) Simultaneous Localization and Mapping.
所以这是我们周五的一位演讲者将谈论他的专业知识（SLAM）同步本地化和制图。
This is a very well-studied and understood problem of detecting unique features in the external scene
这是一个非常充分研究和理解的检测外部场景中的独特特征的问题
and localizing yourself based on the trajectory of those unique features.
并根据这些独特功能的轨迹进行本地化。
When the number of features is high enough it becomes an optimization problem.
当特征数量足够高时，它成为优化问题。
You know this particular lane moved a little bit from frame to frame you can track that information.
您知道这个特定的通道在帧与帧之间移动了一点点，您可以跟踪该信息。
And fuse everything together in order to be able to estimate your trajectory through the three dimensional space.
并将所有内容融合在一起，以便能够通过三维空间估计您的轨迹。
You also have other sensors to help you out.  You have GPS which is pretty accurate, not perfect but pretty accurate.
您还有其他传感器可以帮助您。你有GPS非常准确，不完美，但非常准确。
It's another signal to help you localize yourself.
这是帮助您自己进行本地化的另一个信号。
You also have IMU.  Accelerometer
你也有IMU。加速度计
tells you your acceleration, from the gyroscope, the accelerometer, you have the six degree of freedom
告诉你你的加速度，从陀螺仪，加速度计，你有六个自由度
of movement information about how the moving object, the car, is navigating through space.
关于移动物体，汽车如何在太空中航行的运动信息。
So you can do that using the old school way of optimization.
所以你可以用旧式的优化方式来做到这一点。
Given a unique set of features, like sift features, and that step involves with stereo input understorting and
给定一组独特的功能，如筛选功能，该步骤涉及立体声输入的输入和输入
and rectifying the images.  You have two images, from the two images compute the depth map but for every single pixel
并纠正图像。您有两个图像，从两个图像计算深度图，但每个像素
computing the
计算
best estimate of the depth of that pixel, the three dimensional position, relative to the camera then you
最佳估计该像素的深度，三维位置，相对于相机然后你
compute, that's where you compute the disparity map, that's what that's called, from which you get the distance
计算，这是你计算视差图的地方，也就是所谓的距离
then you detect unique, interesting features in the scene.  Sift is a popular one.
然后你会发现场景中独特，有趣的功能。筛选是一个受欢迎的。
It's a popular algorithm for detecting unique features and you, over time, track those features.
这是一种用于检测独特功能的流行算法，随着时间的推移，您可以跟踪这些功能。
And that tracking is what allows you through the vision alone to get information about your trajectory
而这种跟踪可以让您通过视觉来获取有关您的轨迹的信息
through three-dimensional space.  You estimate that trajectory.  There's a lot of assumptions, assumptions that bodies are rigid.
通过三维空间。你估计那个轨迹。有很多假设，假设身体是僵化的。
So you have to figure out if a large object passes right in front of you, you have to figure out what that was.
所以你必须弄清楚一个大物体是否正好在你面前，你必须弄清楚它是什么。
You have to figure out mobile objects in the scene.  And those are the stationary.
你必须弄清楚场景中的移动对象。那些是静止的。
Or you can cheat or we'll talk about and do it using neural networks end-to-end.
或者你可以作弊或者我们将讨论并使用端到端的神经网络来做。
Now what does end-to-end mean?  And this will come up a bunch of times throughout this class and today.  End-to-end means,
现在端到端意味着什么？在整个班级和今天，这将会出现很多次。端到端意味着，
and I refer to it as cheating because it takes away a lot of the hard work of panageneric features.  You take the raw input
我把它称为作弊，因为它消除了许多panageneric功能的艰苦工作。你接受原始输入
of whatever sensors.  In this case, it's taking stereo input from a stereo vision cameras so two images, a sequence of two
任何传感器。在这种情况下，它从立体视觉相机获取立体声输入，因此两个图像，两个序列
images coming from a stereo vision camera, and the output is a estimate of your trajectory through space.
来自立体视觉相机的图像，输出是对空间轨迹的估计。
So it's supposed to be doing the hard work of SLAM, of detecting unique features, of localizing yourself, of tracking those
所以它应该是SLAM的艰苦工作，检测独特的功能，本地化自己，跟踪那些
features and figuring out where your trajectory is.  You simply train the network.
功能和确定你的轨迹在哪里。你只需训练网络。
With some Ground Truth, you have form a more accurate sensor like lidar,
通过一些地面真相，您可以形成更精确的传感器，如激光雷达，
and you train it on a set of inputs, the stereo vision inputs,
你在一组输入上训练它，立体视觉输入，
and outputs is the trajectory through space.  You have a separate convolutional neural networks for the velocity
和输出是通过空间的轨迹。你有一个单独的卷积神经网络的速度
and for the orientation.  And this works pretty well.  Unfortunately, not quite well
并为方向。这非常有效。不幸的是，不太好
and John Leonard will talk about that.  SLAM is one of the places were deep learning is not being able to outperform the
约翰伦纳德将谈论这个。 SLAM是深度学习无法超越的地方之一
previous approaches.
以前的方法。
Where deep learning really helps is the scene understanding part.  It's interpreting the objects in the scene.
深度学习真正有用的是场景理解部分。它正在解释场景中的对象。
It's detecting the various parts of the scene, segmenting them
它正在检测场景的各个部分，对它们进行分割
and with optical flow determining their movement.  So previous approaches for detecting objects
并用光流确定它们的运动。所以以前检测对象的方法
like the traffic signal, the classification of detection that we have the TensorFlow tutorial for
像交通信号一样，我们有TensorFlow教程的检测分类
or to use car-like features or other types of features that are hard-engineered from the images.
或使用类似汽车的功能或其他类型的功能，这些功能是从图像中精心设计的。
Now we can use convolutional neural networks to replace the extraction of those features.
现在我们可以使用卷积神经网络来取代这些特征​​的提取。
And there's TensorFlow implementation of SegNet
而且还有SegNet的TensorFlow实现
which is taking the exact same neural network that I talked about.  It's the same thing, the beauty is you just apply
这与我所谈到的完全相同的神经网络。这是同样的事情，美丽就是你申请
similar types of networks to different problems
类似的网络类型到不同的问题
and depending on the complexity of the problem, can get quite amazing performance.  In this case, we convolutionize
并且根据问题的复杂性，可以获得相当惊人的性能。在这种情况下，我们卷积
network, meaning the output is an image, input is an image, a single monocular image.  The output is a
网络，意思是输出是图像，输入是图像，单个单眼图像。输出是一个
segmented image where the colors indicate your best pixel-by-pixel estimate of what object is in that part.
分段图像，其中颜色表示您对该部分中对象的最佳逐像素估计。
This is not using any spatial information, it's not using any temporal information.
这不使用任何空间信息，它不使用任何时间信息。
So it's processing every single frame separately and it's able to separate the road from the trees,
所以它分别处理每一帧，它能够将道路与树木分开，
from the pedestrians, other cars, and so on.
来自行人，其他汽车等。
This is intended to lie on top of a radar / lidar type of technology that's giving you the three dimensional
这是为了在雷达/激光雷达类型的技术之上，为您提供三维技术
or stereo vision three-dimensional information about the scene.  You're, sort of, painting that scene with the identity of
或立体视觉有关场景的三维信息。你是那样的，用那个身份画那个场景
the objects that are in it, your best estimate of it.
其中的对象，您对它的最佳估计。
This is something I'll talk about tomorrow is recurring neural networks
我明天会谈到的是反复出现的神经网络
and we can use recurring neural networks that work with temporal data to process video
我们可以使用与时间数据一起处理视频的重复神经网络
and also process audio.  In this case, we can process what's shown on the bottom is
并处理音频。在这种情况下，我们可以处理底部显示的内容
a spectrogram of audio for a wet road and a dry road.
湿路和干路的音频谱图。
You can look at that spectrogram as an image
您可以将该频谱图视为图像
and process it in a temporal way using recurring neural networks.  Just slide it across and keep feeding it to a network.
并使用重复神经网络以时间方式处理它。只需将其滑过并继续将其送入网络即可。
And it does incredibly well on the simple tasks, certainly of dry road versus wet road.  This is important,
它在简单的任务上做得非常好，当然是干路和湿路。这个很重要，
a subtle, but very important task and there's many like it to know the road, the texture, the quality.,
一个微妙但非常重要的任务，有许多人喜欢它来了解道路，质地，质量。
the characteristics of the road, wetness being a critical one.
道路的特点，潮湿是一个关键的。
When it's not raining but the road is still wet, that information is very important.
当它不下雨但道路仍然潮湿时，这些​​信息非常重要。
Okay, so for movement planning.  The same kind of approach.  On the right is work from one of our other speakers
好的，所以对于运动规划。同样的方法。右边是我们其他发言者的作品
Sertec Karaman.  The same approach we're using to solve traffic through friendly competition
塞特卡拉曼。我们通过友好竞争解决流量的方法相同
is the same that we can use for what Chris Gerdes does with his race cars for planning trajectories in high speed movement
我们可以用它来克服Chris Gerdes用他的赛车来计划高速运动的轨迹
along complex curve.
沿着复杂的曲线。
So we can solve that problem using optimization, solve the control problem using optimization,
所以我们可以使用优化来解决这个问题，使用优化解决控制问题，
or we can use it with reinforcement learning by running
或者我们可以通过跑步来加强学习
tens of millions, hundreds of millions of times through that simulation of taking that curve
通过模拟这条曲线，数以千万计，数亿次
and learning which trajectory doesn't both optimizes
并且学习哪个轨迹都没有优化
the speed at which you take the turn
转弯的速度
and the safety of the vehicle.  Exactly the same thing that you're using for traffic.
和车辆的安全性。与您用于流量完全相同的事情。
And for driver state, this is what will talk about next week.  It's all the fun face stuff:  eyes, face, emotion.
对于驾驶员状态，下周将讨论这个问题。这是所有有趣的面孔：眼睛，脸，情感。
This is with video of the driver, video of the driver's body, video the driver's face.  On the left is one of the TAs
这是驾驶员的视频，驾驶员身体的视频，驾驶员面部的视频。左边是其中一个助教
in his younger days.  Still looks the same.  There he is.  So in that particular case,
在他年轻的时候。看起来仍然一样。他在那。所以在那种特殊情况下，
you're doing one of the easier problems which is one of detecting where the head and the eyes are positioned.
你正在做一个比较简单的问题，就是检测头部和眼睛的位置。
The head and eye pose.  You know it determine what's called
头部和眼睛的姿势。你知道它决定了什么叫做
he gaze of the driver, where the driver's looking, glance.  And so,
他凝视着司机，司机在看，瞥了一眼。所以，
we'll talk about these problems.  From the left to the right:  on the left in green are the easier problems; on the red
我们将谈论这些问题。从左到右：绿色左边是更容易出问题;在红色
are the harder from the computer vision aspect.
从计算机视觉方面来说更难。
So on the left is body pose, head pose.  The larger the object the easier it is the detect
所以在左边是身体姿势，头部姿势。物体越大，检测越容易
and the orientation of it is easier to detect.
并且它的方向更容易检测。
And then there is pupil diameter.  Detecting the pupil, the characteristics, the position, the size of the pupil.
然后有瞳孔直径。检测瞳孔，瞳孔的特征，位置，大小。
And there's micro saccade, things that happen
还有微观的扫视，发生的事情
at one millisecond frequency, the tremors of the eye.  All important information to determine the state of the driver.
在一毫秒的频率，眼睛的震颤。确定驱动程序状态的所有重要信息。
Some are possible computer vision, some are not.  This is something that we'll talk about, I think, on Thursday.
有些是可能的计算机视觉，有些则不是。我想，这是我们周四要谈的内容。
Is the detection of where the driver's looking.  So, this is a bunch of the cameras that we have in the Tesla.  This is
是检测驾驶员的样子。所以，这是我们在特斯拉的一堆相机。这是
This is Dan driving a Tesla and detecting exactly where of one of six regions
这是Dan驾驶特斯拉并准确探测六个地区之一的位置
We've converted into a classification problem of left, right, rear view mirror instrument cluster center stack
我们已经转换成左，右，后视镜仪表组中心堆栈的分类问题
or forward roadway. So we have to determine out of those six categories
或前进道路。因此，我们必须确定这六个类别
which direction is the driver looking at.  This is important for driving.  We don't care exactly the X, Y, Z
司机看哪个方向。这对驾驶很重要。我们并不关心X，Y，Z
position of where the driver is looking at.  We care that they're looking at the road or not.
司机所在的位置。我们关心的是他们正在寻找道路。
Are they looking at their cell phone in their lap or are they looking at the forward roadway?
他们是在看着他们的手机还是看着前方的车道？
And we'll be able to answer that pretty effectively using convolutional neural networks.
我们将能够使用卷积神经网络非常有效地回答这个问题。
You can also look at emotion using CNNs to extract,
您还可以使用CNN来提取情绪，
again converting emotion, the complex world of emotion, into a binary problem of frustrated versus satisfied.
再次将情感，复杂的情感世界转化为沮丧与满足的二元问题。
This is the video of drivers interacting with a voice navigation system.  If you've ever used one,
这是与语音导航系统交互的驱动程序的视频。如果你曾经使用过一个，
you know that may be a source of frustration from folks.
你知道这可能是人们沮丧的根源。
And so this is self reported, this is one of the hard, you know, driver
所以这是自我报道，这是一个很难知道的驱动程序
emotion if you're in what's called "Effective Computing."  It's the field of studying emotion from the computational side.
如果你正处于所谓的“有效计算”中，那就是情感。这是从计算方面研究情感的领域。
If you work in that field,
如果你在那个领域工作，
you know that the annotation side of emotion is really challenging one.
你知道情绪的注释方面真正具有挑战性。
So getting the Ground Truth of, well okay since this guy's smiling
因此，获得地面真相，好吧，因为这家伙的笑容
so can I label that as happy or he's frowning because that mean he's sad.  Most effective computing folks do just that.
所以我可以将其标记为快乐或者他皱眉，因为这意味着他很伤心。最有效的计算人员就是这么做的。
In this case we self report ask people how frustrated they're were in a scale of 1 to 10.
在这种情况下，我们自我报告询问人们他们在1到10的范围内是多么沮丧。
Dan up top reported a "1" for not frustrated, he's satisfied with the interaction,
Dan up top报告了一个“1”因为没有沮丧，他对这种互动感到满意，
and the other driver reported as a "9" he was very frustrated with the interaction.  And what you notice
另一名司机报告为“9”，他对这种互动感到非常沮丧。而你注意到了什么
is there is a very cold, stoic look on Dan's face which is an indication of happiness.
Dan的脸上是否有一种非常寒冷，坚忍的表情，这表明幸福。
And in the case of frustration, the driver is smiling.
在沮丧的情况下，司机正在微笑。
So this is a sort of a good reminder that we can't trust our own human instincts.
所以这是一个很好的提醒，我们不能相信我们自己的人类本能。
It's an engineering feature.  Engineering the ground truth.  We have to trust the data, trust the Ground Truth
这是一项工程特色。设计基本事实。我们必须信任这些数据，相信地面真相
that we believe is the closest reflection of the actual semantics of what's going on in the scene.
我们相信这是对场景中发生的事实的实际语义的最接近的反映。
Okay, so end-to-end driving.  Getting to the the project and the tutorial.
好的，所以端到端的驾驶。进入项目和教程。
So if driving is like a conversation and, thank you for someone to clarifying, that this is the Arch of Triumph
因此，如果驾驶就像一次谈话，并且感谢有人澄清，那就是凯旋门
in Paris in this video.
在这个视频中的巴黎。
If driving is like a natural language conversation, then we can think of end-to-end driving as skipping the entire Turing Test
如果驾驶就像是一种自然语言对话，那么我们可以将端到端驾驶视为跳过整个图灵测试
components and treating it as an end-to-end natural language generation.
组件并将其视为端到端的自然语言生成。
So what we do is we take as input the external sensors
所以我们做的是将外部传感器作为输入
and output, the control of the vehicle.  And the magic happens in the middle.
和输出，车辆的控制。魔术发生在中间。
We replace that entire step with a neural network.
我们用神经网络替换整个步骤。
TAs told me to not include this image because it's the cheesiest we've ever seen.  I apologize.  Thank you, thank you.
TA告诉我不要包含这张图片，因为它是我们见过的最好的图片。我道歉。谢谢谢谢。
I regret nothing.
我一点儿都不后悔。
So this is to show our path to self-driving cars
所以这是展示我们自动驾驶汽车的道路
but it still explain a point that we have a large data set of Ground Truth.
但它仍然解释了我们拥有大量地面真相数据集的观点。
If we were to formulate the driving task to simply taking external images
如果我们要制定驾驶任务来简单地拍摄外部图像
and producing steering commands, acceleration of braking commands, then we have a lot of Ground Truth.
并产生转向指令，加速制动指令，然后我们有很多地面真相。
We have a large number of drivers on the road every day driving
我们每天都有大量的司机在路上行驶
and, therefore, collecting our Ground Truth for us because they're an interested party in producing the steering commands
因此，我们收集了我们的基本真相，因为他们是生产转向命令的感兴趣的一方
that keep them alive and, therefore, if we were to record that data it becomes Ground Truth.
让它们保持活力，因此，如果我们要记录这些数据，它就变成了真相。
So if it's possible to learn this,
所以，如果有可能学到这一点，
what we can do is we can collect data for the manually controlled vehicles
我们能做的是我们可以为手动控制的车辆收集数据
and use that data to train an algorithm to control a self-driving vehicle.
并使用该数据训练算法以控制自动驾驶车辆。
Okay, so one of the first folks who did this is Nvidia where they actually train in an external image, the image of the forward roadway.
好吧，所以第一个做这件事的人之一就是Nvidia，他们实际上在外部图像中训练，即前方道路的图像。
and a neural network, a convolutional network, a simple vanilla convolutional neural network I'll briefly outline:
和神经网络，卷积网络，简单的香草卷积神经网络我将简要概述：
take an image in, produce a steering command out
拍摄图像，产生转向命令
and they're able to successfully, to some degree, learn to navigate basic turns, curves and even stop
并且他们能够在某种程度上成功地学习导航基本转弯，曲线甚至停止
or make sharp turns at a keener section.  So this this now work is simple.
或者在更敏感的部分急转弯。所以现在这个工作很简单。
There is input on the bottom, output up top.  The input is a 66x200 pixel image, RGB.
底部有输入，顶部输出。输入是一个66x200像素的图像RGB。
Shown on the left is the raw input and then you crop it a little bit and resize it down
左边显示的是原始输入，然后稍微裁剪它并调整大小
66x200.   That's what we have in the code as well in the two versions of the code we'll provide to you.
66x200。这就是我们在代码中以及我们将为您提供的两个代码版本中的内容。
Both that runs in the browser and in TensorFlow.  It has a few layers.  A few convolutional layers, a few fully connected layers.
它们都在浏览器和TensorFlow中运行。它有几层。一些卷积层，一些完全连接的层。
And an output.  This is a regression network.
并输出。这是一个回归网络。
It's producing not a classification of cat versus dog, it's producing a steering command.
它产生的不是猫与狗的分类，而是产生转向命令。
How do I turn the steering wheel?  That's it.  The rest is magic and we train it on a human input.
我该如何转动方向盘？而已。剩下的就是魔术，我们在人力投入上进行训练。
What we have here is a project, is an implementation of the system in ConvNetJS that runs in your browser.
我们这里有一个项目，是在您的浏览器中运行的ConvNetJS系统的实现。
This is the tutorial to follow and the project to take on.  So unlike the DeepTraffic game, this is reality.
这是要遵循的教程和要采取的项目。因此，与DeepTraffic游戏不同，这是现实。
This is a real input from real vehicles.
这是来自真实车辆的真实输入。
So you can go to this link.  Demo went wonderfully yesterday so let's see, maybe two for two.
所以你可以去这个链接。演示昨天非常精彩，所以让我们看看，也许是两个人。
There's the tutorial and then the actual game, the actual simulation is on DeepTesla.JS, I apologize.
有教程，然后是实际游戏，实际模拟是在DeepTesla.JS上，我道歉。
Everyone is going there now, aren't they?  Does it work on a phone?  It does, great.
现在每个人都去那里，不是吗？它适用于手机吗？它确实很好。
Again similar structure up top is the visualization of the lost function as the network is learning
顶部的类似结构再次是网络学习时丢失功能的可视化
and it's always training.
而且它总是在训练。
Next is the input for the layout of the network, there's the specification of the input 200x66.
接下来是网络布局的输入，输入200x66的规格。
There's a convolutional layer. There's a pooling layer and the output is a regression layer.  A single neuron.
有一个卷积层。有一个池层，输出是一个回归层。一个神经元。
This is a tiny version, DeepTiny, right?  It's a tiny version of
这是一个很小的版本，DeepTiny，对吗？这是一个很小的版本
the Nvidia architecture and then you can visualize the operation of this network on real video.
Nvidia架构，然后您可以在真实视频上可视化此网络的运行。
The actual wheel value that produced by the driver, by the autopilot system,
由驾驶员，自动驾驶系统产生的实际车轮值，
is in blue and the output of the network is in white.
为蓝色，网络输出为白色。
And what's indicated by green is the cropping of the image that is then resized to produce the 66x200
而绿色表示的是图像的裁剪，然后调整大小以生成66x200
input to the network.  So once again, amazingly, this is running in your browser, training on real world video.
输入到网络。再一次，令人惊讶的是，这是在您的浏览器中运行，对现实世界视频进行培训。
So you can get in your car today input it and maybe teach a neural network to drive like you.
所以今天你可以进入你的车里输入它，也许可以像你一样教一个神经网络。
We have the code in ConvNetJS
我们在ConvNetJS中有代码
and TensorFlow to do that and the tutorial.  Well, let me briefly describe some of the work here.
和TensorFlow这样做和教程。好吧，让我简要介绍一下这里的一些工作。
So the input to the network as a single image.
因此将网络输入作为单个图像。
This is for DeepTesla.JS, single image and the output is a steering wheel value between -20 and 20.
这适用于DeepTesla.JS，单个图像，输出是-20到20之间的方向盘值。
That's in degrees.  We record,
这是度数。我们记录，
like I said, thousands of hours but we provide publicly 10 video clips of highway driving from a Tesla.
就像我说的，数千小时，但我们公开提供了10个特斯拉公路驾驶的视频剪辑。
Half are driven by autopilot, half are driven by human.  The wheel values extracted from a perfectly synchronized
一半由自动驾驶仪驱动，一半由人类驱动。从完美同步中提取的车轮值
CAN, we are collecting all of the messages from CAN,
CAN，我们正在收集来自CAN的所有消息，
which contains steering wheel value and that's synchronized to the video.  We crop, extract the window.  The green one I mentioned.
其中包含方向盘值并与视频同步。我们裁剪，提取窗口。我提到的绿色。
And then provide that as input to the network.
然后将其作为网络的输入提供。
So this is a slight difference from DeepTraffic with the red car weaving through traffic because there is the messy
所以这与DeepTraffic的区别在于红色汽车在交通中编织，因为有杂乱
reality of real world lighting conditions.
现实世界的照明条件。
And your task for the most part, in this simple steering task, is to stay inside the lane,
在这个简单的转向任务中，你的大部分工作就是留在车道内，
inside the lane markings.  In an end-to-end way, learn to do just that.  So ConvNetJS
在车道标记内。以端到端的方式，学会做到这一点。所以ConvNetJS
is a javascript implementation of CNNs, of convolutional neural networks.  It supports really arbitrary networks.
是卷积神经网络的CNN的javascript实现。它支持真正的任意网络。
I mean all neural networks are simple but because it runs in javascript it's not utilizing GPU.
我的意思是所有神经网络都很简单，但因为它在javascript中运行，所以它不使用GPU。
The larger the network the more it's going to be weighed down computationally.
网络越大，计算量就越大。
Now unlike DeepTraffic, this isn't a competition
现在不像DeepTraffic，这不是竞争
but if you are a student registered for the course you still do have to submit the code, you still have to submit your own
但如果您是注册该课程的学生，您仍然需要提交代码，您仍然需要提交自己的代码
car as part of the class.  Question.  So the question was the amount of data that's needed.
汽车作为班级的一部分。题。所以问题是需要的数据量。
Is there a general rules of thumb for the amount of data needed for a particular task in driving for example?
例如，驾驶特定任务所需的数据量是否有一般的经验法则？
It's a good question.
这是一个很好的问题。
You generally have to, like I said, neural networks are good memorizers so you have to just have every case represented in the
你通常不得不像我说的那样，神经网络是很好的存储器，所以你必须让每个案例都代表
training said that you're interested in.  As much as possible, so that means, in general if you want a picture, if you want to
训练说你感兴趣。尽可能的，这意味着，一般来说，如果你想要一张照片，如果你想
classify the difference between cats and dogs, you want to have at least a thousand cats and a thousand dogs
分类猫狗之间的差异，你想拥有至少一千只猫和一千只狗
and they do really well.  The problem with driving is twofold:  one, is that most of the time driving looks the same.
而且他们做得很好。驾驶的问题是双重的：一，驾驶的大部分时间看起来都是一样的。
And the stuff you really care about is when driving looks different.  It's all the edge cases.
而你真正关心的是驾驶时看起来与众不同。这是所有边缘情况。
So we're not good with neural networks is generalizing from the common case to the edge cases, to the outliers.
因此，我们对神经网络的不善，从普通情况到边缘情况，再到异常值。
So avoiding a crash
所以避免崩溃
just because you can stand the highway for thousands of hours successfully doesn't mean you can avoid a crash with
只因为你能够成功地站在高速公路上数千小时并不意味着你可以避免撞车
somebody runs in front of you on the road
有人跑在你面前的路上
and the other part with driving is the accuracy you have to achieve is really high.  So for cat versus dog,
而驾驶的另一部分是你必须达到的准确度非常高。所以对于猫与狗，
No, life doesn't depend on your error.  On your ability to steer a car inside of the lane.
不，生活不依赖于你的错误。关于你在车道内驾驶汽车的能力。
You better be very close to 100% accurate. There's a box for designing the network.
你最好接近100％准确。有一个用于设计网络的盒子。
There's a visualization of the metrics measuring the performance of the network as it trains.
可以看到衡量网络性能的指标。
There is a visualization, layer visualization, of what features the network is extracting at every convolutional layer
有一个可视化，层可视化，网络在每个卷积层提取的功能
and every fully connected layer.  There is ability to restart the training.
和每个完全连接的层。有能力重新开始培训。
Visualize the network performing on real video.  There is the input layer, the convolutional layers.
可视化在真实视频上执行的网络。有输入层，卷积层。
The video visualization, an interesting tidbit on the bottom right is a barcode that Will has ingeniously designed.
视频可视化，右下方有趣的花絮是Will巧妙设计的条形码。
How do I clearly explain why this is so cool?
我如何清楚地解释为什么这么酷？
It's a way to through video synchronized multiple streams of data together,
这是一种通过视频同步多个数据流的方式，
so it's very easy for those who have worked with multi-modal data where there are several streams of data
因此，对于那些使用多模态数据的人来说，这里有很多数据流非常容易
for them to become unsynchronized especially when a big component of training a neural network is shuffling the data.
因为它们变得不同步，特别是当训练神经网络的一个重要组成部分正在改变数据时。
So you have to shuffle the data in clever ways
因此，您必须以巧妙的方式对数据进行洗牌
so you're not overfitting any one little aspect of the video and yet maintain the data perfectly synchronized.
因此，您不会过度拟合视频的任何一个方面，而是保持数据完全同步。
So what he did instead doing the hard work of connecting the steering wheel
所以他做的是做连接方向盘的艰苦工作
and in the video is actually putting the steering on top of the video as a barcode.
并且在视频中实际上将转向作为条形码放在视频之上。
The final result is you can watch the network operate and over time it learns more and more to steer correctly.
最终的结果是你可以观察网络的运行情况，并且随着时间的推移，它会越来越多地学习正确驾驶。
I'll fly through this a little bit in the interest of time just kind of summarize some of the things that you can play
为了时间的缘故，我会稍微通过这一点，只是总结一些你可以玩的东西
with in terms of tutorials and let you guys go.  This is the same kind of process end-to-end driving with
在教程方面，让你们去。这是与端到端驱动相同的过程
So we have code available on GetHub.  You just put up on my GetHub and the DeepTesla.
所以我们在GetHub上提供了代码。你刚刚放上我的GetHub和DeepTesla。
That takes in a single video or an arbitrary number of videos trains on them
这需要一个视频或任意数量的视频列车
and produces a visualization that compares the steering wheel, the actual steering wheel and the predicted steering wheel.
并产生一个可视化，比较方向盘，实际方向盘和预测的方向盘。
The steering wheel, when it agrees with the human driver or the autopilot system lighting up as green
方向盘，当它与人类驾驶员或自动驾驶系统一起点亮为绿色时
and when it disagrees, lighting up as red.  Hopefully not too often.
当它不同意时，点亮为红色。希望不要经常。
Again, this is some of the details of how that's exactly done in TensorFlow.
同样，这是TensorFlow中如何完成的一些细节。
This is vanilla convolution neural networks.
这是香草卷积神经网络。
Specifying a bunch of layers, convolutional layers, a fully connected layer, train the model, so you iterate over the batches of images.
指定一堆图层，卷积图层，完全连接的图层，训练模型，以便迭代批量图像。
Run the model over a test set of images and get this result.  We have a tutorial
在一组测试图像上运行模型并获得此结果。我们有一个教程
on iPython Notebook into the tutorial up on this.
在iPython Notebook上进入这个教程。
This is perhaps the best way to get started with convolutional neural networks in terms of our class.  It's looking at the
这可能是我们课堂上开始使用卷积神经网络的最佳方法。它在看着
simplest image classification problem, of traffic light classification.  So we have these images of traffic lights.
最简单的图像分类问题，交通灯分类。所以我们有这些交通信号灯的图像。
We did the hard work of detecting them for you.
我们为您做了很好的检测。
So now you have to figure out, you have to build the convolutional network that gets
所以现在你必须弄清楚，你必须构建得到的卷积网络
figures out the concept of color and gets excited when it sees red, yellow or green.  If anyone has questions,
弄清楚颜色的概念，当它看到红色，黄色或绿色时会变得兴奋。如果有人有疑问，
I'll welcome those.  You can stay after class if you have any concerns with Docker,
我会欢迎那些。如果您对Docker有任何疑虑，可以在课后留下，
with TensorFlow, with how to win DeepTraffic.  Just stay after class or come by Friday, 5 to 7.  See you guys tomorrow.
与TensorFlow一起，如何赢得DeepTraffic。下课后或5点到7点周五来。请明天见。